William Johnson Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
William Johnson Papers in the Charles E. Feinberg Collection 1944-1945
MSS60582
Feinberg, Charles E., 1899-
Johnson, William, 1771-1834
30 items
2 containers
0.6 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Supreme Court justice. Chiefly holograph manuscripts, typescripts, and printed copies of a series of articles concerning Johnson written by Abraham J. Levin and published in the Michigan Law Review.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Feinberg, Charles E., 1899-1988 collector.; Johnson, William, 1771-1834.; Johnson, William, 1771-1834. William Johnson papers in the Charles E. Feinberg collection. 1944-1945.; Levin, Abraham J., 1897- Abraham J. Levin papers. 1944-1945.
Organizations
Charles E. Feinberg Collection (Library of Congress); United States. Supreme Court.
Titles
Charles E. Feinberg papers
Occupations
Collectors.; Judges.; Justices, U.S. Supreme Court.; Lawyers.
Provenance
The papers of William Johnson, associate justice of the United States Supreme Court, in the Charles E. Feinberg Collection were given to the Library of Congress by Feinberg in 1982.
Transfers
Printed volumes have been transferred to the Library's Rare Book and Special Collections Division where they are identified as part of the William Johnson Papers.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of William Johnson are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of William Johnson (1771-1834) in the Charles E. Feinberg Collection consist of a series of articles concerning Johnson published in the Michigan Law Review by Abraham J. Levin, 1944-1945. The collection includes holograph manuscripts, typescripts, printed copies, and miscellaneous items documenting the writing and editing of Levin's articles. A two-volume set of Johnson's Sketches of the Life and Correspondence of Nathanael Greene (Charleston, S.C.: [Printed by A. E. Miller], 1822) has been transferred to the Rare Book and Special Collections Division of the Library of Congress.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged alphabetically by type of material.
Container List
- "Mr. Justice William Johnson and the Common Incidents of Life," Michigan Law Review, 1945, Aug. and Oct. (Box 1)
  - Drafts, circa 1945, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Miscellany, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Printed copy, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Typescripts, circa 1945 (Box 1)
    - Manuscripts (Box 1)
    - Miscellany (Box 1)
- "Mr. Justice William Johnson and the Unenviable Dilemma," Michigan Law Review, 1944, Apr. (Box 2)
- "Mr. Justice William Johnson, Creative Dissenter," Michigan Law Review, 1944, Dec. (Box 2)
  - Draft, circa 1944 (Box 2)
  - Printed copy, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Typescript, circa 1944 (Box 2)